Joey Gauthier Web Developer / UXUI

AngularJS

JavaScript

MVC / MVVM Design

Application Architecture

Personal Statement

Having worked in many different technical fields, picking up new skills and adapting to change is second nature to me now. Between all of the apps I currently have in production I've gone from backend to frontend, Ruby on Rails to JavaScript, and graphic designer to server administrator / development operations. When my work isn't pushing me to learn new skills I spend time writing apps and scripts to automate and enrich my life and I take online classes to learn more languages and freameworks. Technology is a part of my identity.

I found my calling to write code while working as an IT professional for IBM. Writing scripts to automate tasks saved me time and effort and led to me writing full applications that combine all of my previous work into a GUI. I realized that I enjoyed the problem solving involved in writing code and I haven't stopped since.

Work Experience

From Oct 2014 Till Now:

For the past year I've been working as a UXUI / Frontend Developer for Schneider Electric. My duties have been to help create new data visualization applications from the ground up using Angular, Node, Express, Mongo, and several chart and table frameworks.

from Nov 2008 till July 2014:

During this period I was an IT professional with IBM supporting AT&T. When I wasn't troubleshooting a client's computer or a site network issue, I was writing code to do it all for me.

from Nov 2006 till Feb 2010:

I was owner and operator of Mobile PC Experts which had me fixing computers for consumers and businesses.

Technologies

JavaScript

AngularJS

NodeJS

ExpressJS

MongoDB

Kendo UI

D3

Gridster

ChartJS

Angular Material

Ruby on Rails

Python

PHP

Postrges

VBScript

Flex

Bash

Soap

Education

MakerSquare

July 2014 - Oct 2014 Immersive Dev Bootcamp Ruby, Rails, JS, HTML, CSS

Midwestern State

University

Sep 1999 - Dec 2000

Computer Science

C++ and algorithms